<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Android App Example</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">IG3 - Développement mobile</string>
    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">Anne SMAL &amp; Lisa TRAPLETTI</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="menu_module_1">Module 1</string>
    <string name="menu_module_2">Module 2</string>
    <string name="menu_module_3">Module 3</string>

    <string name="module_title_start">Start</string>


    <string name="title_activity_welcome">Welcome !</string>

    <string name="welcome_title">Welcome !</string>
    <string name="welcome_description">Through this application, you will learn how to develop an Android mobile app.
        Use it as an example : Go to the source code, test it with some rotation, plane mode, …
        So that you will discover how to create your own super project. \n
        OK, time to dive into the amazing Android World !
    </string>

    <!-- Module 1 Activities and Fragments -->
    <string name="module_1_title">Activities &amp; Fragments</string>
    <string name="module_1_description">Activities and fragments are the basis of a mobile application,
        as they are representing your entire User Interface. \n
        In this chapter, you will learn what is an activity, a fragment, and how Android OS is working
        with them.
    </string>

    <string name="module_1_activity_lifecycle_title">Activity lifecycle</string>

    <string name="module_1_what_is_an_activity_title">What is an Activity ?</string>
    <string name="module_1_what_is_an_activity_description">An <b>activity</b> provides the window
        in which the app draws its UI. Generally, one activity implements one screen of the app. \n
        Typically, one activity in an app is specified as the <b>main</b> activity,
        which is the <b>first screen to appear when the user launches the app</b>.
        Each activity can then start another activity in order to perform different actions.
        \n \n

        Of course, you can navigate through your own activities; But Android also permits to start
        the main activity of other applications installed on the smartphone, in order to use a functionality of those.
        Click on the next button to check and go to through the code to see how this navigation is implemented.
    </string>

    <string name="module_1_how_to_use_activities">To use activities in your app, you must register
        information about them in the app\'s manifest. Go to the AndroidManifest.xml to check the
        activities our application contains.</string>

    <string name="module_1_go_to_camera">Use camera</string>

    <string name="module_1_what_is_a_fragment"> As you can check, we didn\'t create an activity
        for each screen of our app. It is because we decided to use <b>fragments</b>, combined to
        our activities. \n \n
        A <b>fragment</b> is a piece of user interface, used in an activity.
        Fragments have been introduced by Android for app development on bigger devices, such as tablets :
        As a fragment is only a "piece" of UI, you can combine multiple fragments in a single activity
        to build a multi-pane UI and reuse a fragment in multiple activities. \n
        Start an emulator of a tablet size, and check in the code how it is implemented.
    </string>

    <string name="module_1_multipane_fragment">See ? I can decide to add multiple fragments in a
        single activity at the same time. You can think of a fragment as a modular section of an activity,
        which has its own lifecycle, receives its own input events, and which you can add or remove
        while the activity is running. \n
        To continue this tutorial, use back your smartphone emulator.
    </string>

    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>


    <!-- Module 2 Layouts -->
    <string name="module_2_title">Layouts</string>
    <string name="module_2_description">Layouts are XML files \"assembling\" all the UI components together.
        Each activity and each fragment will, at least, be linked to one layout. \n
        In this chapter, you will learn what is a layout, how to create one and how to link it to
        an activity, a fragment, or another UI component.
    </string>

    <string name="module_2_layout_structure_title">Layout Structure</string>


    <!-- Module 3 Resources -->
    <string name="module_3_title">Resources</string>
    <string name="module_3_description">TO COMPLETE
    </string>

    <string name="module_3_resources_types_title">Resources Types</string>
    <string name="title_activity_first_module">FirstModuleActivity</string>

    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="previous">Previous</string>
</resources>
